<article xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
	 xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
	 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
	 xml:lang="es">

  <title>Human Skills</title>
  <articleinfo>
    <authorgroup>
      <author>
	<surname>Chappell</surname>
	<firstname>David</firstname>
	<affiliation>
	  <orgname>Procter and Gamble</orgname>
	  <address><email>chappell.da@pg.com</email></address>
	</affiliation>
      </author>
      <othercredit>
	<surname>Imass</surname>
	<firstname>Alejandro</firstname>
	<authorblurb>
	  <para>
	    This text was part of a presentation ("Applying S88 - The
	    Human Factor") shown at the World Batch Forum Chicago
	    2004, and I asked Dave permission to use it this part of
	    the text for personal matters. I constantly use this scale
	    to grade myself on the different skills and disciplines
	    that I work in and to explain to other people what these
	    levels mean, so I reference them here instead of copying
	    and re-distributing this content in my own documents.  If
	    you are reading this, it is because I referenced this URL
	    from another document solely for the purposes expalined
	    above. If you have got here by any other means (Google or
	    mere accident) please do not copy or otherwise use this
	    information without contacting David Chappel at the e-mail
	    address above and get his written permission or contact me
	    to explain why you would like to link or use this
	    information and I in turn will contact David and explain
	    it to him.
	  </para>
	</authorblurb>
      </othercredit>
    </authorgroup>
  </articleinfo>
  <para>
    All individuals develop Skills throughout their lives. There are far
    too many Skill Areas for all people to be exposed to every one, so we
    must all pick and choose which ones are important to us, both in our
    personal and professional lives.
  </para>
  <para>
    Many skill areas depend upon other skill areas, and when you have
    a large enough grouping it can be thought of as a
    Discipline. Mathematics provides a good example of a
    discipline. There are many basic skill areas, such as addition,
    subtraction, multiplication, and division. All higher level
    mathematic disciplines, such as geometry and algebra require these
    basic skills.
  </para>
  <para>
    As a person develops capability in a skill area, there are
    different levels of proficiency they can expect to achieve. This
    is based upon many factors. Some dominating factors are personal
    aptitude, personal attitude, training, technical mentoring, and
    experience.
  </para>
  <para>
    Continuing with the mathematics example: as students learn basic
    arithmetic, they receive training using textbooks and instruction
    from a teacher. Some students with the right
    <emphasis>"aptitude"</emphasis> will get the concepts very quickly
    and progress rapidly in their proficiency to apply that
    skill. Others will require more mentoring by the teacher to
    progress. <emphasis>Only by "experience"</emphasis> or practice,
    practice, practice will anyone truly learn a skill. Some skills
    require a lot more practice than others.
  </para>
  <para>
    <emphasis>
      Personal attitude (open and questioning versus arrogant and
      self-important) plays a significant role in individual success
      or failure in this development process. It takes a great amount
      of mentoring to overcome the wrong attitude, and many mentors
      are not willing to invest the necessary energy and time.
    </emphasis>
  </para>
  <para>
    Proper mentoring <emphasis>can overcome aptitude</emphasis>, and
    help individuals achieve their highest "level of capability". On
    the other hand, inadequate mentoring can provide people with the
    opportunity to learn many good lessons from their mistakes. This
    latter process is very ineffective as it only teaches "what not to
    do next time", without any advice on "what to do the next time".
    <emphasis> A proper balance between inadequate mentoring and
    over-mentoring (dictatorship, actually) must be maintained, so as
    not to squash innovation.  </emphasis> There are many ways that
    these levels of capability can be measured. Grades in education
    are one:
  </para>
  <para>
    A - Excellent, B - Good, C - Average, D - Inadequate and F  Failing. 
  </para>
  <section>
    <title>The Human Skills Grading System</title> 
    <para>
      What were your math grades? One grading system that I find
      useful in industry is represented in the 5 categories, or
      levels, shown in the following Figure:
    </para>
    <graphic fileref="figure1.svg" scale="40"/>
    <para>
      These categories are beginner, novice, apprentice, expert and
      master. As the pyramid suggests, there are always a lot more
      people at the lower levels than the upper. The common
      characteristics of each level are described in the Table below:
      Common Skills Categories and Characteristics.
    </para>
    <table>
      <title>
	Common Skill Categories Level Common Skills Categories and
	Characteristics
      </title>
      <tgroup cols="2">
	<tbody>
	  <row>
	    <entry>Beginner</entry>
	    <entry>
	      Beginners have the "book-knowledge" of what the skill or
	      discipline is about. They have little to no practical
	      knowledge or experience, and <emphasis>they require
	      constant attention</emphasis>. At this stage, they have
	      an awareness of what they are about, with little to no
	      real knowledge on what to do with their "bookknowledge".
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>Novice</entry>
	    <entry>
	      Novices have progressed to the point of general,
	      real-world, practical knowledge about the skill or
	      discipline. They <emphasis>usually feel they have
	      mastered the technology, and they will proceed to apply
	      it with marginal results</emphasis>. They
	      generally<emphasis> don't know enough to understand what
	      they don't know</emphasis>, and they require a great
	      amount of direction from those who have a higher level
	      of skill. If an individual never advances beyond this
	      level, <emphasis>they often feel and act as if they have
	      achieved a much higher level than they are entitled
	      to</emphasis>, leading to confusion and failed
	      endeavors. They are often energetic, enthusiastic, and
	      fearless in the application of the skill or discipline.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>Apprentice</entry>
	    <entry>
	      Apprentices have progressed to the point where they have
	      effective practical knowledge about the skill or
	      discipline, and they can successfully apply that
	      knowledge. Some people are quite happy to stay at this
	      level, and they decide not to invest additional effort
	      to advance. <emphasis>Others have no choice, as they
	      have reached the highest level that they are capable of
	      achieving, and no amount of effort will enable them to
	      advance. <emphasis>A few will progress on to the higher
	      skill levels.</emphasis> </emphasis>They have respect
	      for what they are doing, and they know what not to do,
	      <emphasis>and when to seek advice</emphasis>.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>Expert</entry>
	    <entry>
	      Experts have advanced beyond practical knowledge to
	      <emphasis>deep understanding, and they can leverage
	      their skills in ways that have never been thought of
	      before</emphasis>. They are able to mentor the beginners
	      and novices and provide resource help for the
	      apprentices.
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>Master</entry>
	    <entry>
	      <emphasis>Masters have acquired wisdom</emphasis> as
	      well as understanding, and they are able to incorporate
	      new learning back into the skill or discipline in such a
	      way that novices and apprentices can make use of them.
	      <emphasis> A master can advance a discipline and improve
	      a technology.</emphasis> Masters must take care as they
	      use their skill, <emphasis>so those outside the
	      discipline do not get a false impression as to the ease
	      with which a discipline can be applied.  Often those
	      outside a discipline will expect master level
	      performance from apprentice and lower
	      individuals.</emphasis>
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	</tbody>
      </tgroup>
    </table>
    <para>
      If you have a sufficient capability level in a related skill or
      discipline, moving through the lower skill categories in a new
      skill area can require much less time. Take physics, for
      example. If you have achieved to an expert level of capability
      in geometry and algebra, getting to an apprentice level in
      physics can be achieved much more quickly and successfully than
      if your starting point is a master level in government.
    </para>
    <para>
      While both individuals are excellent intellectually and are
      performing well overall, one will have an advantage over the
      other in developing capability in the new skill area of
      physics. It doesnt indicate the final level of capability each
      will achieve, just how quickly and with how much effort each
      will be able to move to the apprentice level. Then the practice,
      practice, practice starts. As you can guess, it is very
      difficult, and perhaps impossible, to predict who will excel at
      a discipline, how long it will take them to advance, and who
      will and will not make it. When developing someones skill,
      <emphasis>it is generally possible to force them to the
      apprentice level. Moving beyond that level requires desire and
      effort on the part of the individual <emphasis>and can not be
      forced by any organization or person.</emphasis></emphasis>
    </para>
  </section>
</article>
