<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<article xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
	 xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
	 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
	 xml:lang="en">
  
  <title>Alberto Mijares</title>

  <subtitle>DevOps Engineer - Information Technologies and
  Data Security Consultant</subtitle>
  

  <sect1 label="">
    <title>Personal Information</title>
    <para>
      <literallayout>
	Name: Alberto José Mijares Paredes
	Birth Date: October 23, 1979
	Birthplace: Caracas, Venezuela
	Marital Status: Married
      </literallayout>
    </para>
        <address>
      <email>amijaresp@gmail.com</email>
      <street>
	Av. Independencia #901, torre G-34, apto. B7. Zona Universitaria.
      </street>
      <city>Santo Domingo</city>
      <state>Distrito Nacional</state>
      <postcode>10103</postcode>
      <country>Dominican Republic</country>
      <phone id="cellphone">+1(849)858.92.46</phone>
    </address>

    <sect2 label="">
      <title>Personal Profile</title>
      <para>
	I see myself as a solutions provider. My fundamentals are:
	stick to the standards, follow the principles of Unix and
	write good documentation.
      </para>
      <para>
	I work very well socially, which is key for management
	positions. I like karaoke parties and cooking with
	friends. Eventually, I go out for running or swimming, wich
	helps me to not get too fat (I love eating).
      </para>
    </sect2>
  </sect1>
  <sect1 label="">
    <title>Skills</title>
    <para>
      The next section points my skills in different IT
      disciplines. The levels have been graduated according the next
      scale:
    </para>
    <simplelist>
      <member>[M] Master</member>
      <member>[E] Expert</member>
      <member>[A] Apprentice</member>
      <member>[N] Novice</member>
      <member>[P] Beginner</member>
    </simplelist>
    <para>
      For more details about this scale please read the electronic
      document <ulink url="https://www.mcs.com.ve/hs/">The Human Skills
      Grading System</ulink>.
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <title>Programming Languages</title>
      <listitem>
	<para>[A+] Perl 5 (apprentice, becoming expert)</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	<para>[P] Haskell, C</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	<para>[E] Bourn Shell (Shell Scripting)</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <itemizedlist>
      <title>Operative Systems</title>
      <listitem>
	<para>[E] FreeBSD</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	<para>[A+] Debian GNU/Linux, CentOS, Ubuntu Server</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <itemizedlist>
      <title>Databases</title>
      <listitem>
	<para>[E] PostgreSQL, MySQL</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <itemizedlist>
      <title>Orchestation</title>
      <listitem>
	<para>[E] Ansible</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <itemizedlist>
      <title>Virtualization</title>
      <listitem>
	<para>[E] Bhyve, KVM, VirtualBox</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <itemizedlist>
      <title>Services and Applications</title>
      <listitem>
	<para>
	  Apache, Nginx, Sendmail, Postfix, OpenSMTPD, Dovecot,
	  AntiSPAM, Packet Filter (PF), Squid, Snort, Bro, Suricata,
	  Nagios, Munin, NTP, DHCP, Bind, Unbound, ELK stack, UWSGI,
	  IPSec, Git, Asterisk, RADIUS, OpenLDAP, Kannel, Metasploit
	  Framework and many others. The level for all these items is
	  located between A and E.
	</para>
	<para>
	  I also have experience working with CMS's like Wordpress,
	  e-Commerce solutions like Magento, educative portals like
	  Moodle, tracking systems like Request Tracker (RT),
	  management systems like dotProject and Redmine, CRM's like
	  SugarCRM, accounting software like GNUCash, personal cloud
	  storage with ownCloud, print servers with CUPS, SAMBA, NFS,
	  FTP, ZFS, etc.
	</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    
  </sect1>
  <sect1 label="">
    <title>Working Experience</title>
    <para>
      I've been working in the field of Information Technologies for
      more than 15 years, starting from basic support activities for
      end users until getting into very complex activities like the
      planification and execution of projects for mission-critical
      tasks. I also have had the opportunity for teach, wich is a
      great enriching experience.
    </para>
    <para>
      My confort zone is in around the FreeBSD project, which provides
      an excellent OS, documentation and development ecosystem;
      accompanied by an excellent community of hackers. I also was
      very savvy in the Linux world some years ago; however, the
      latest changes introduced into the main distributions have
      dissappointed me a lot. This is a matter of preference, though,
      I can work on any Unix-like environment.
    </para>
    <para>
      My orientation has always been biased to what happens in the
      backstages (Infrastructure/Arquitechture) instead of the
      scenaries (User Experience/Interfaces), closely related to
      develoment cycles (DevOps). That's true even before this
      terminology came to existence.
    </para>
    <para>
      My working experience can be splited in two: projects
      executed as freelance consultant and positions occupied in some
      companies.
    </para>
    
    <sect2>
      <title>Positions</title>      
      <sect3>
	<title>Future Link Corporation (2016 - 2017)</title>
	<sect4>
	  <title>VP Engineering</title>
	  <para>
	    While I still was in Venezuela, Future Link sponsored my
	    work permit and visa for Dominican Republic. In my short
	    period with this company I was able to:
	  </para>
	  <itemizedlist>
	    <listitem>
	      <para>
		Perform a PCI compliance self-asessment and suggest
		improvements.
	      </para>
	    </listitem>
	    <listitem>
	      <para>
		Participate in the recruitment process of a Junior
		System Adminitrator, giving my recommendations for a
		specific candidate, who resulted elected and was able to
		perform assigned tasks with outstanding results.
	      </para>
	    </listitem>
	    <listitem>
	      <para>
		Re-assign resources from one project to another, where
		the deadline was very close and manpower was required.
	      </para>
	    </listitem>
	    <listitem>
	      <para>
		Creation and update of required packages within the
		framework pkgsrc, from NetBSD. Server updates.
	      </para>
	    </listitem>
	  </itemizedlist>
	</sect4>
      </sect3>  
      
      
      <sect3 label="">
	<title>Higher Institute of Technological Studies and
	Investigations - ISEIT (2006 - 2010)</title>
	<sect4 label="">
	  <title>Instructor</title>
	  <itemizedlist>
	    <listitem>
	      <para>
		Member of professors staff, mainly for the "Certified
		Linux Administrator" program.
	      </para>
	    </listitem>
	  </itemizedlist>
	</sect4>
      </sect3>
      <sect3 label="">
	<title>"La Villa del Cine" Foundation (2008)</title>
	<sect4 label="">
	  <title>Networking and Telecommunications Coordinator</title>
	  <itemizedlist>
	    <listitem>
	      <para>
		Network and systems administration. Coordination of tech
		support staff. Migration of private solutions to FOSS
		alternatives.
	      </para>
	    </listitem>
	  </itemizedlist>
	</sect4>
      </sect3>
      
      <sect3 label="">
	<title>Corcaribe Tecnología, C.A.(2007 - 2008)</title>
	<sect4 label="">
	  <title>Network Administrator - Consultant</title>
	  <itemizedlist>
	    <listitem>
	      <para>
		Maintenance of the IT platform. Consultancy for external
		customers. Specialized support.
	      </para>
	    </listitem>
	  </itemizedlist>
	</sect4>
      </sect3>
      
      <sect3 label="">
	<title> Economic and Social Development Bank of Venezuela -
	BANDES (2006-2007)</title>
	<sect4 label="">
	  <title>Tech Assistant</title>
	  <itemizedlist>
	    <listitem>
	      <para>
		Structured cabling. Data and voice networks
		maintenance. PBX administration.
	      </para>
	    </listitem>
	  </itemizedlist>
	</sect4>
	<sect4 label="">
	  <title>Security Information Analyst</title>
	  <itemizedlist>
	    <listitem>
	      <para>
		Monitoring, review and updating of the institution's
		security policies.
	      </para>
	    </listitem>
	    <listitem>
	      <para>
		Penetration Testing - Ethical Hacking
	      </para>
	    </listitem>
	    <listitem>
	      <para>
		Monitor compliance of established policies. Checking of
		procedures for communications and data exchange between
		financial and government institutions.
	      </para>
	    </listitem>
	    <listitem>
	      <para>
		Research
	      </para>
	    </listitem>
	  </itemizedlist>
	</sect4>
      </sect3>
      
      
      <sect3 label="">
	<title>Teravision Technologies (2005-2006)</title>
	<sect4 label="">
	  <title>Network Administrator</title>
	  <itemizedlist>
	    <listitem>
	      <para>
		Internal customers support. Creation and maintenance of
		LAN services. Network rewiring and hiring of new ISP.
	      </para>
	    </listitem>
	    <listitem>
	      <para>
		Migration of version control system from CVS on Win32 to
		SVN on Linux.
	      </para>
	    </listitem>
	    <listitem>
	      <para>
		Setup of a HA database cluster for
		applications. Separation of development and production
		environments.
	      </para>
	    </listitem>
	    <listitem>
	      <para>
		Creation and implementation of a BCP for the development
		team.
	      </para>
	    </listitem>
	    <listitem>
	      <para>
		Maintenance of a software appliance.
	      </para>
	    </listitem>
	  </itemizedlist>
	</sect4>
      </sect3>
      
      <sect3 label="">
	<title>World Tel-Fax Electronics, C.A. (2001-2005)</title>
	<sect4 label="">
	  <title>Telephone Operator (2001-2002)</title>
	  <itemizedlist>
	    <listitem>
	      <para>
		Call center operator. Search of specialized information
		service <trademark>INFO-LINE</trademark>.
	      </para>
	    </listitem>
	  </itemizedlist>
	</sect4>
	<sect4 label="">
	  <title>Transcriptor - Information Department (2002)</title>
	  <itemizedlist>
	    <listitem>
	      <para>
		Data transcribers team coordination. Creation of
		reporting and statistics tools, QA, productivity
		measuring, among others.
	      </para>
	    </listitem>
	  </itemizedlist>
	</sect4>
	<sect4 label="">
	  <title>Audio Operator (2002-2003)</title>
	  <itemizedlist>
	    <listitem>
	      <para>
		Recording, edition and conversion of audio clips for IVR
		systems and multimedia contents.
	      </para>
	    </listitem>
	  </itemizedlist>
	</sect4>
	<sect4 label="">
	  <title>Tech Support (2003-2005)</title>
	  <itemizedlist>
	    <listitem>
	      <para>
		Internal and external customers support. Preventive and
		corrective maintenance or workstations. PBX
		administration.
	      </para>
	    </listitem>
	    <listitem>
	      <para>
		Servers and network monitoring: Routers, Gateway SMS,
		IVR's, Switches, web server - Email - Databases, Web
		Proxy-Cache, Portmaster, PBX, DNS, DHCP.
	      </para>
	    </listitem>
	    <listitem>
	      <para>
		Soporte de aplicaciones. Mantenimiento de usuarios del
		sistema.
	      </para>
	    </listitem>
	  </itemizedlist>
	</sect4>
      </sect3>
    </sect2>

    <sect2>
      <title>Projects</title>
      
    <sect3 label="">
      <title>Freelance Consultant (2008 - 2016)</title>
      <para>
	Along almost 9 years of activities as a consultant, I've been
	involved in many projects and activities. Here are the most
	important projects, the company involved and a short
	description with some achievements:
      </para>
      
      <sect4>
	<title>Upstream Bandwidth Optimization</title>
	<subtitle>Aeronet, C.A.</subtitle>
	<para>
	  Aeronet is a <foreignphrase>Wireless ISP</foreignphrase> in
	  Venezuela. They needed to optimize the available upstream
	  Bandwidth for their customers.
	</para>
	<para>
	  Overall, upstream traffic was optimized by a 24% and the
	  end-user experience was improved by 32%, thanks to higher
	  download rates in average. The solution was implemented
	  using the Squid Proxy on a server with a fine tuned
	  FreeBSD.
	</para>
      </sect4>

      <sect4>
	<title>Virtualization</title>
	<subtitle>National Housing and Habitat Bank</subtitle>
	<para>
	  BANAVIH (for its initials in spanish) is the offical
	  institution in Venezuela for habitational loans and
	  subcidy. They needed to optimize the hardware utilization in
	  their datacenter.
	</para>
	<para>
	  A total of 4 servers were freed and repourposed, thanks to
	  the application of the virtualization technology in
	  development and testing servers; saving thousands of dollars
	  in hardware adquirance. Red Hat Enterprise Linux and Xen
	  were the technoligies used in this project.
	</para>
      </sect4>
      
      <sect4>
	<title>Migration of Email and Domain Controller services to
	Open Source Solutions</title>
	<subtitle>CONVIASA</subtitle>
	<para>
	  CONVIASA is a venezuelan airline. The objectives of the
	  project were the migration of email services and primary
	  domain controller to open source solutions.
	</para>
	<para>
	  The email services was migrated from third-party provider to
	  a self-hosted solution based on Red Hat Enterprise 5,
	  Postfix, Dovecot and Roundcube as web interface. The PDC was
	  implemented on Debian with Samba3 with group-based custom
	  profiles on workstations. Both services were integrated with
	  OpenLDAP as the backend for users identification and
	  authentication. The airline achieved the compliment 
	</para>
      </sect4>

      <sect4>
	<title>Web form for issuing policies</title>
	<subtitle>Pyugmao Fondos Administrados, C.A.</subtitle>
	<para>
	  Pyugmao is a risk manager company, providing Civil Liability
	  Policies to their customers. They needed a centralized
	  system to generate policies.
	</para>
	<para>
	  A web form was developed in the Perl programming languaje
	  with the CGI interface and PostgreSQL for the database. The
	  company was able to increase their salesforce and to emit
	  more than ten times more policies monthly, compared to the
	  months before the implementation of the solution.
	</para>
      </sect4>
      
      <sect4>
	<title>Interface for BT-3000 Plus Chemistry Analyzer</title>
	<subtitle>Neat Systems, C.A.</subtitle>
	<para>
	  Neat Systems is a development company specialized in ERP
	  Software for hospitals and laboratories, running on the
	  Windows platform. The <emphasis>BT-3000 Plus Chemistry
	  Analyzer</emphasis> has a serial communication protocol via
	  DB9 COMM Port, which makes it difficult to integrate into
	  the TCP/IP network.
	</para>
	<para>
	  A webservice was developed, implementing the serial protocol
	  and making it available via HTTP. The solution was written
	  in Perl on Debian Linux, and embeded in a VirtualBox image,
	  so it can be run inside a Windows server.
	</para>
      </sect4>

	<sect4>
	  <title>Digicheck2</title>
	  <subtitle>Bayco, C.A.</subtitle>
	  <para>
	    Bayco is a security solutions provider for the banking
	    industry in Venezuela. They lost the control over a
	    product they owned, due to some discordance with the
	    former developers of the product. I was able to
	    reverse-engineering the product and implement it using
	    open source technologies. I gave them back the control
	    over the product by writing detailed documentation about
	    how their product works, how was developed and how can be
	    modified.
	  </para>
	  <para>
	    The rewrite was made with Perl, using the framework
	    Mojolicious, PortgreSQL and Debian Linux. A customization
	    of the debian-installer was made in order to include the
	    corporative image of Bayco. The functionality of the
	    product was to take a screenshot of face, check and id
	    document when a client goes to the bank to cash a check.
	  </para>
	</sect4>

	<sect4>
	  <title>High Availability in VoIP</title>
	  <subtitle>FIDES, C.A.</subtitle>
	  <para>
	    FIDES is a company providing medical services through a
	    call center. The requirement was a setup such that if the
	    main VoIP PBX server fails, the spare can't take more than
	    20 seconds for the failover.
	  </para>
	  <para>
	    The goal was achieved combining spacialized hardware from
	    <trademark>Digium</trademark> and replication techniques
	    on Elastix.
	  </para>
	</sect4>

	<sect4>
	  <title>Load Balancing Cluster</title>
	  <subtitle>inmobilia.com</subtitle>
	  <para><emphasis>inmobilia.com</emphasis> is a real state web
	  portal with presence in 13 countries. The initial setup for
	  their portal went out of capacity when they reached 4 hits
	  per second. I designed for them a mixed cluster with virtual
	  and bare metal servers, with defined roles as
	  <foreignphrase>loadbalancers</foreignphrase>,
	  <foreignphrase>backends</foreignphrase> and
	  <foreignphrase>databases</foreignphrase>. I also leaded the
	  development team into the <emphasis>Git Branching
	  Model</emphasis> workflow, documented in <ulink
	  url="http://http://nvie.com/posts/a-successful-git-branching-model/">this
	  article by Vincent Driessen</ulink>. Finally, I configured
	  an Amazon S3 bucket for the bank of images of the portal
	  (about 160 GB by that time) and helped to integrate the
	  stoage service in the portal.
	  </para>
	  <para>
	    The performance increased drastically, holding loads of
	    above 30 requests per socond with no significant impact on
	    the servers, whose could handle up to 5 times such load
	    without penalties. This implementation is saving money by
	    using virtual servers for most of the hosts and not
	    requiring huge amounts of aditional storage for backups.
	  </para>
	</sect4>

	<sect4>
	  <title>Recovery of files from <trademark>Glacier</trademark></title>
	  <subtitle>inmobilia.com</subtitle>
	  <para>
	    The development team of inmobilia.com tried to implement
	    the versioning feature from S3 service. However, they made
	    a mistake and sent all their images to Glacier, where they
	    are not available online. Even with paid support from AWS,
	    they were unable to recover the files.
	  </para>
	  <para>
	    Using the API from AWS S3 I wrote I script in Perl making
	    parallel request, which helped to recover the files 16
	    times faster than the time required if we used the methods
	    suggested by AWS support. You can take a look at the
	    script at https://github.com/granalberto/s3mu.
	  </para>
	</sect4>
	    
	  
	
    </sect3>
    </sect2>
  </sect1>  
  
  <sect1 label="">
    <title>Training: Specialized Courses and Certifications</title>
    <sect2 label="">
      <title>IT Courses and Certifications</title>
      <sect3 label="">
	<title>
	  Network Management
	</title>
	<segmentedlist>
	  <segtitle>Description</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Institution</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Instructor</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Duration</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Certification granted</segtitle>
	  <seglistitem>
	    <seg>
	      Best practices in technical and management aspect for
	      data and voice networks. Available tools, configuration
	      and use.
	    </seg>
	    <seg>
	      Central University of Venezuela - Faculty of Engineering
	    </seg>
	    <seg>
	      Prof. Vicenzo Mendillo (UCV)
	    </seg>
	    <seg>
	      32 hours
	    </seg>
	    <seg>
	      Certificate of approval
	    </seg>
	  </seglistitem>
	</segmentedlist>	  
      </sect3>
      <sect3 label="">
	<title>Linux Professional Certified Program</title>
	<segmentedlist>
	  <segtitle>Description</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Institution</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Instructor</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Duration</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Certificate granted</segtitle>
	  <seglistitem>
	    <seg>
	      Basic and advanced administration of Linux-based
	      operative systems. Theoretic and ideological roots of free
	      software movement. Unix-like environments tool set.
	    </seg>
	    <seg>
	      Higher Institute of Technological Studies and
	      Investigations (ISEIT)
	    </seg>
	    <seg>
	      Ing. Carlos García - Ing. Jesús Rivero
	    </seg>
	    <seg>
	      80 hours
	    </seg>
	    <seg>
	      Certified Linux Administrator Professional
	    </seg>
	  </seglistitem>
	</segmentedlist>
      </sect3>

      <sect3 label="">
	<title>Linux Security Professional</title>
	<segmentedlist>
	  <segtitle>Description</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Institution</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Instructor</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Duration</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Certificate granted</segtitle>
	  <seglistitem>
	    <seg>
	      Basis of information security concepts. Tools and
	      methodologies for security policies implementations.
	    </seg>
	    <seg>
	       Higher Institute of Technological Studies and
	      Investigations (ISEIT)
	    </seg>
	    <seg>
	      Ing. Ricardo Strusberg
	    </seg>
	    <seg>
	      32 hours
	    </seg>
	    <seg>
	      Certified Linux Security Administrator Professional 
	    </seg>
	  </seglistitem>
	</segmentedlist>
      </sect3>

      <sect3 label="">
	<title>Linux Networks Administrator</title>
	<segmentedlist>
	  <segtitle>Descripción</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Institución</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Instructor</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Duración</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Certificado Emitido</segtitle>
	  <seglistitem>
	    <seg>
	      Netwoking concepts, services and open source
	      implementations.
	    </seg>
	    <seg>
	      Higher Institute of Technological Studies and
	      Investigations (ISEIT)
	    </seg>
	    <seg>
	      Ing. Ernesto Hernandez-Novich
	    </seg>
	    <seg>
	      32 hours
	    </seg>
	    <seg>
	      Certified Linux Networks Administrator Professional
	    </seg>
	  </seglistitem>
	</segmentedlist>
      </sect3>

      <sect3 label="">
	<title>LPI Certification</title>
	<segmentedlist>
	  <segtitle>Institute</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Certificate granted</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>LPI ID</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Verification Code</segtitle>
	  <seglistitem>
	    <seg>Linux Professional Institute</seg>
	    <seg>Junior Linux Certified Professional (LPIC-1)</seg>
	    <seg>LPI000092165</seg>
	    <seg>k3z5ham8ph</seg>
	  </seglistitem>
	</segmentedlist>
      </sect3>
      
      <sect3 label="">
	<title>Agile Development Workshop with Python</title>
	<segmentedlist>
	  <segtitle>Description</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Institution</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Instructor</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Duration</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Certificate granted</segtitle>
	  <seglistitem>
	    <seg>
	      Tools for agile development of user interfaces with
	      Python
	    </seg>
	    <seg>
	      V Foro Mundial del Conocimiento Libre
	    </seg>
	    <seg>
	      Ing. Francisco Palm
	    </seg>
	    <seg>
	      8 hours
	    </seg>
	    <seg>
	      Certificate of participation
	    </seg>
	  </seglistitem>
	</segmentedlist>
      </sect3>
      
    </sect2>
    <sect2 label="">
      <title>Professional and Personal Growth Courses</title>

      <sect3 label="">
	<title>Voice and Diction</title>
	<segmentedlist>
	  <segtitle>Descriptio</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Instructor</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Duration</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Certificate granted</segtitle>
	  <seglistitem>
	    <seg>
	      Voice manipulation for professional purposes.
	    </seg>
	    <seg>
	      Lic. Adriana Romero
	    </seg>
	    <seg>
	      8 hours
	    </seg>
	    <seg>
	      Certificate of Approval
	    </seg>
	  </seglistitem>
	</segmentedlist>
      </sect3>

      <sect3 label="">
	<title>Job Analysis</title>
	<segmentedlist>
	  <segtitle>Description</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Institution</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Duration</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Certificate granted</segtitle>
	  <seglistitem>
	    <seg>
	      Position Analysis
	    </seg>
	    <seg>
	      INCE
	    </seg>
	    <seg>
	      40 hours
	    </seg>
	    <seg>
	     Certificate of Approval
	    </seg>
	  </seglistitem>
	</segmentedlist>
      </sect3>

      <sect3 label="">
	<title>Psychology Applied to the Supervision</title>
	<segmentedlist>
	  <segtitle>Descripction</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Institution</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Duration</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Certificate granted</segtitle>
	  <seglistitem>
	    <seg>
	      Management of work situations and leadership.
	    </seg>
	    <seg>
	      INCE
	    </seg>
	    <seg>
	      20 hours
	    </seg>
	    <seg>
	     Certificate of Approval
	    </seg>
	  </seglistitem>
	</segmentedlist>
      </sect3>
      
      <sect3 label="">
	<title>Quality-oriented Management</title>
	<segmentedlist>
	  <segtitle>Description</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Institution</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Duration</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Certificate granted</segtitle>
	  <seglistitem>
	    <seg>
	      Concepts and strategies for process
	      optimization. Continuous improvement.
	    </seg>
	    <seg>
	      INCE
	    </seg>
	    <seg>
	      100 hours
	    </seg>
	    <seg>
	     Certificate of Approval
	    </seg>
	  </seglistitem>
	</segmentedlist>
      </sect3>
    </sect2>
  </sect1>

  <colophon>
    <title>About this document</title>
    <para>
      This document was produced using the DocBook 5 schema with XSL
      stylesheets, Emacs 25 as text editor and Apache FOP for its
      publication in PDF.
    </para>
    <para>
      You can check the source code for this document in
      https://github.com/granalberto/cv/docbook5/ajmp-cv-en.xml.
    </para>
  </colophon>
</article>
