<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<article xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
	 xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
	 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
	 xml:lang="en">
  
  <title>Curriculum Vitae: Alberto Mijares</title>

  <subtitle>IT Projects Manager, Infrastructure Architect and
  <trademark>UNIX</trademark> Support Specialist</subtitle>

  <articleinfo>
    <revhistory>
      <revision>
	<revnumber>3.0</revnumber>
	<date>June 2025</date>
	<revremark>Adding NeatCSS for web and updating information</revremark>
      </revision>
      <revision>
	<revnumber>2.9</revnumber>
	<date>July 2017</date>
	<revremark>Moving to Docbook 5 from Docbook 4</revremark>
      </revision>
      <revision>
	<revnumber>1.0</revnumber>
	<date>July 2008</date>
	<revremark>Based on <link
	xlink:href="https://github.com/aimass">Alejandro
	Imass's</link> CV</revremark>
      </revision>
    </revhistory>
  </articleinfo>
  
  <sect1>
    <title>Personal Information</title>
    <para>
      <literallayout>
	Full Name: Alberto José Mijares Paredes
	Birthplace: Caracas, Venezuela
      </literallayout>
    </para> 
    <address>
      <email>amijaresp@gmail.com</email>
      <street>
	San Bernardino</street>
      <city>Caracas</city>
      <state>Distrito Capital</state>
      <postcode>1010</postcode>
      <country>Venezuela</country>
      <phone id="cellphone">+58(412)5938582</phone>
    </address>

    <sect2>
      <title>About me...</title>
      <para>
	I see myself as a solutions provider. My fundamentals are:
	stick to the standards, follow the principles of Unix (simple
	is beautiful) and write good documentation.
      </para>
      <para>
	I'm honest, reserved and focused. I align myself with the
	vision of my clients and nothing is executed without profit,
	seen from different viewpoints.
      </para>
      <sect3>
	<title>What am I doing now?</title>
	<para>
	  I provide specialized support services for the
	  infrastructure of a company that operates as a job board in
	  the state of Nebraska, through the company <link
	  xlink:href="https://zvitech.com">ZVI Technologies</link>,
	  based in the Dominican Republic.
	</para>
	<para>
	  I'm also in charge of editing videos for <link
	  xlink:href="https://youtube.com/@rabinoshui">Rabbi Shui
	  Rosenblum's YouTube channel</link>, in his daily delivery of
	  Chumash studies. I use <link
	  xlink:href="https://www.openshot.org">OpenShot</link> and
	  <link
	  xlink:href="https://www.audacityteam.org">Audacity</link>
	  for these tasks.
	</para>
      </sect3>
    </sect2>
  </sect1>

  <sect1>
    <title>Knowledge and Skills</title>
    <para>
      This is a non-exahustive list of the skills developed along my careerpath.
    </para>
    <sect2>
      <title>Soft Skills</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <title>Management</title>
      <listitem>
	<para>
	  Self-Management throught time management techniques. Mainly,
	  TODO lists and Calendars help me to get things done.
	</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	<para>
	  Agile Management with Scrum-based techniques. While not
	  strictly attached to any theory, I can identify segments
	  that help me to manage a certain team for achieving certain
	  goals. It shpuld be dynamic as projects are dynamic.
	</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	<para>
	  Lidership by example and data-driven decision-making. I'm a
	  good team pleayer when the roles, objetives and processes
	  are well defined.
	</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <itemizedlist>
      <title>Communications</title>
      <listitem>
	<para>
	  Good verbal and written communication.
	</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	<para>
	  Active listening.
	</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	<para>
	  Persuasion and negotiation. Always trying to get the win-win
	  formula.
	</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <itemizedlist>
      <title>Problem-Solving and Critical Thinking</title>
      <listitem>
	<para>
	  Problems come in different flavors and the job is to solve
	  them so that the business continues to run.
	</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	<para>
	  Every issue is divided in smaller issues and each one is
	  analyzed under criticism for getting in to the best
	  workaround and finally a definitive solution.
	</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <itemizedlist>
      <title>Learning Agility and Personal Development</title>
      <listitem>
	<para>
	  I'm a self taught person and I'm always reading newsletters
	  about Business, Information Technologies, e-Commerce and
	  related subjects for being always up-to-date with the latest
	  services and products.
	</para>
	<para>
	  I also read technical bulletins and engineering blogs from
	  the top companies in the information technologies field.
	</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    </sect2>

    <sect2>
      <title>Hard Skills</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <title>Programming Languages</title>
      <listitem>
	<para>Perl 5 and the Mojolicious Web Development Framework</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	<para>Haskell, C (still learning)</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	<para>Bourn Shell and Python Scripting</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <itemizedlist>
      <title>Operative Systems</title>
      <listitem>
	<para>FreeBSD for servers operative systems and appliance
	development</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	<para>Debian GNU/Linux, CentOS, Ubuntu Server and other Linux
	flavors</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	<para>
	  Software packaging for FreeBSD with <link
	  xlink:href="https://www.freshports.org">The Ports
	  Collection</link>, for Debian according to their <link
	  xlink:href="https://www.debian.org/doc/debian-policy/">packaging
	  policies</link> and basically for any unix-based operative
	  system with <link xlink:href="https://www.pkgsrc.org/">pkgsrc</link>.
	</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <itemizedlist>
      <title>Databases</title>
      <listitem>
	<para>PostgreSQL, MySQL and MariaDB for SQL DB Engines</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <itemizedlist>
      <title>Orchestration</title>
      <listitem>
	<para>Ansible, Jenkins</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <itemizedlist>
      <title>Virtualization</title>
      <listitem>
	<para>Bhyve, KVM, VMWare and VirtualBox</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    </sect2>
    <sect2>
      <title>Services and Applications</title>
	<para>
	  Besides those skills, I also have experience with many
	  toolsets. I wish I could name all the technologies,
	  services, software and tools that I know and have worked
	  with, but such list would be too long. Instead, please read
	  the section about projects I have worked on my own and
	  representing other companies.
	</para>
    </sect2>
 
  </sect1>

  <sect1 label="">
    <title>Working Experience</title>
    <para>
      I've been working in the field of Information Technologies for
      more than 22 years, starting from basic support activities for
      end users until getting into very complex activities like the
      planning and execution of projects for mission-critical
      tasks. I also have had the opportunity to teach, which is a
      great enriching experience.
    </para>
    <para>
      My comfort zone is in around the FreeBSD project, which provides
      an excellent OS, documentation and development ecosystem;
      accompanied by an excellent community of hackers. I also was
      very savvy in the Linux world some years ago; however, the some
      changes introduced a few years ago into the main distributions
      have disappointed me a lot. This is a matter of preference,
      though, I can work on any Unix-like environment.
    </para>
    <para>
      My orientation has always been into what happens in the
      backstage (Infrastructure/Architecture) instead of the
      scenarios (User Experience/Interfaces), closely related to
      development cycles (DevOps). That's true even before this
      terminology came to existence.
    </para>
    <para>
      My working experience can be splitted in two: projects
      executed as freelance consultant and positions occupied in some
      companies.
    </para>
    
    <sect2>
      <title>Positions</title>
      <sect3>
	<title>Venelectronics</title>
	<sect4>
	  <title>Projects Manager (2023 - 2024)</title>
	  <para>
	    Venelectronics is a retail store with 5 branches in
	    Venezuela. There are many challeneges associated to the
	    politics, taxes and laws in Venezuela, making it harder to
	    run a retail store and spacially in the ecommerce world.
	  </para>
	  <para>
	    I have been in charge of the execution of small projects
	    for the customization of their CRM software, trying to
	    align it with the products and promotions launched by the
	    Marketing Department and others.
	  </para>
	</sect4>
      </sect3>
      <sect3>
	<title>Group of HighTech Companies in New York</title>
	<sect4>
	  <title>Office Manager</title>
	  <para>
	    Since year 2019 to 2022, I've been managing an
	    offshore company, dedicated to software development in
	    Dominican Republic, for a group of companies in the
	    Internet Services business, located in New York, USA.
	  </para>
	  <para>
	    My main tasks are to provide the physical space, services,
	    equipment and facilites for the operations of the
	    developers. I also run campaigns for hiring the developers
	    and make a first approach in order to filter according to
	    non-technical assessments.
	  </para>
	</sect4>
      </sect3>
      <sect3>
	<title>SmartTechDo</title>
	<sect4>
	  <title>Support Specialist (2017 - 2019)</title>
	  <para>
	    Working at SmartTechDo was a great experience. Basically,
	    I provided solutions to complex problem within the
	    ifrastruture of our clients.
	  </para>
	  <para>
	    I spent a lot of time reading documentation of software
	    (open source mostly) figuring out how to improve the
	    behavior of the platform that we were supporting.
	  </para>
	  <para>
	    Some of the technologies that I supported by the time was:
	    <itemizedlist>
	      <listitem>
		<para>
		  ClusterLabs high availability stack
		</para>
	      </listitem>
	      <listitem>
		<para>
		  PCI compliance fixes in systems configuration
		</para>
	      </listitem>
	      <listitem>
		<para>
		  Moodle learning system
		</para>
	      </listitem>
	      <listitem>
		<para>
		  Asterisk IP-PBX
		</para>
	      </listitem>
	    </itemizedlist>
	  </para>
	</sect4>
      </sect3>
      <sect3>
	<title>Future Link Corporation (2016 - 2017)</title>
	<sect4>
	  <title>VP Engineering</title>
	  <para>
	    While I still was in Venezuela, Future Link sponsored my
	    work permit and visa for Dominican Republic. In my short
	    period with this company I was able to:
	  </para>
	  <itemizedlist>
	    <listitem>
	      <para>
		Perform a PCI compliance self-assessment and suggest
		improvements.
	      </para>
	    </listitem>
	    <listitem>
	      <para>
		Participate in the recruitment process of a Junior
		System Administrator, giving my recommendations for a
		specific candidate, who resulted elected and was able to
		perform assigned tasks with outstanding results.
	      </para>
	    </listitem>
	    <listitem>
	      <para>
		Identify problems on time. An example of a suggested
		solution to one of those problems was to re-assign
		resources from one project to another, where the
		deadline was very close and manpower was required.
	      </para>
	    </listitem>
	    <listitem>
	      <para>
		Creation and update of required packages within the
		framework pkgsrc, from NetBSD. Server updates.
	      </para>
	    </listitem>
	  </itemizedlist>
	</sect4>
      </sect3>  
      
      
      <sect3 label="">
	<title>Higher Institute of Technological Studies and
	Investigations - ISEIT (2006 - 2010)</title>
	<sect4 label="">
	  <title>Instructor</title>
	  <itemizedlist>
	    <listitem>
	      <para>
		Member of professors staff, mainly for the "Certified
		Linux Administrator" program.
	      </para>
	    </listitem>
	  </itemizedlist>
	</sect4>
      </sect3>
      <sect3 label="">
	<title>"La Villa del Cine" Foundation (2008)</title>
	<sect4 label="">
	  <title>Networking and Telecommunications Coordinator</title>
	  <itemizedlist>
	    <listitem>
	      <para>
		Network and systems administration. Coordination of tech
		support staff. Migration of private solutions to FOSS
		alternatives.
	      </para>
	    </listitem>
	  </itemizedlist>
	</sect4>
      </sect3>
      
      <sect3 label="">
	<title>Corcaribe Tecnología, C.A.(2007 - 2008)</title>
	<sect4 label="">
	  <title>Network Administrator - Consultant</title>
	  <itemizedlist>
	    <listitem>
	      <para>
		Maintenance of the IT platform. Consultancy for external
		customers. Specialized support.
	      </para>
	    </listitem>
	  </itemizedlist>
	</sect4>
      </sect3>
      
      <sect3 label="">
	<title> Economic and Social Development Bank of Venezuela -
	BANDES (2006-2007)</title>
	<sect4 label="">
	  <title>Tech Assistant</title>
	  <itemizedlist>
	    <listitem>
	      <para>
		Structured cabling. Data and voice networks
		maintenance. PBX administration.
	      </para>
	    </listitem>
	  </itemizedlist>
	</sect4>
	<sect4 label="">
	  <title>Security Information Analyst</title>
	  <itemizedlist>
	    <listitem>
	      <para>
		Monitoring, review and updating of the institution's
		security policies.
	      </para>
	    </listitem>
	    <listitem>
	      <para>
		Penetration Testing - Ethical Hacking
	      </para>
	    </listitem>
	    <listitem>
	      <para>
		Monitor compliance of established policies. Checking of
		procedures for communications and data exchange between
		financial and government institutions.
	      </para>
	    </listitem>
	    <listitem>
	      <para>
		Research
	      </para>
	    </listitem>
	  </itemizedlist>
	</sect4>
      </sect3>
      
      
      <sect3 label="">
	<title>Teravision Technologies (2005-2006)</title>
	<sect4 label="">
	  <title>Network Administrator</title>
	  <itemizedlist>
	    <listitem>
	      <para>
		Internal customers support. Creation and maintenance of
		LAN services. Network rewiring and hiring of new ISP.
	      </para>
	    </listitem>
	    <listitem>
	      <para>
		Migration of version control system from CVS on Win32 to
		SVN on Linux.
	      </para>
	    </listitem>
	    <listitem>
	      <para>
		Setup of a HA database cluster for
		applications. Separation of development and production
		environments.
	      </para>
	    </listitem>
	    <listitem>
	      <para>
		Creation and implementation of a BCP for the development
		team.
	      </para>
	    </listitem>
	    <listitem>
	      <para>
		Maintenance of a software appliance.
	      </para>
	    </listitem>
	  </itemizedlist>
	</sect4>
      </sect3>
      
      <sect3 label="">
	<title>World Tel-Fax Electronics, C.A. (2001-2005)</title>
	<sect4 label="">
	  <title>Telephone Operator (2001-2002)</title>
	  <itemizedlist>
	    <listitem>
	      <para>
		Call center operator. Search of specialized information
		service <trademark>INFO-LINE</trademark>.
	      </para>
	    </listitem>
	  </itemizedlist>
	</sect4>
	<sect4 label="">
	  <title>Transcriptor - Information Department (2002)</title>
	  <itemizedlist>
	    <listitem>
	      <para>
		Data transcribers team coordination. Creation of
		reporting and statistics tools, QA, productivity
		measuring, among others.
	      </para>
	    </listitem>
	  </itemizedlist>
	</sect4>
	<sect4 label="">
	  <title>Audio Operator (2002-2003)</title>
	  <itemizedlist>
	    <listitem>
	      <para>
		Recording, edition and conversion of audio clips for IVR
		systems and multimedia contents.
	      </para>
	    </listitem>
	  </itemizedlist>
	</sect4>
	<sect4 label="">
	  <title>Tech Support (2003-2005)</title>
	  <itemizedlist>
	    <listitem>
	      <para>
		Internal and external customers support. Preventive and
		corrective maintenance or workstations. PBX
		administration.
	      </para>
	    </listitem>
	    <listitem>
	      <para>
		Servers and network monitoring: Routers, Gateway SMS,
		IVR's, Switches, web server - Email - Databases, Web
		Proxy-Cache, Portmaster, PBX, DNS, DHCP.
	      </para>
	    </listitem>
	    <listitem>
	      <para>
		Support for end-users and external costumers.
	      </para>
	    </listitem>
	  </itemizedlist>
	</sect4>
      </sect3>
    </sect2>

    <sect2>
      <title>Projects</title>
      
    <sect3 label="">
      <title>Freelance Consultant (2008 - 2016)</title>
      <para>
	Along almost 9 years of activities as a consultant, I've been
	involved in many projects and activities. Here are the most
	important projects, the company involved and a short
	description with some achievements:
      </para>
      
      <sect4>
	<title>Upstream Bandwidth Optimization</title>
	<subtitle>Aeronet, C.A.</subtitle>
	<para>
	  Aeronet is a <foreignphrase>Wireless ISP</foreignphrase> in
	  Venezuela. They needed to optimize the available upstream
	  Bandwidth for their customers.
	</para>
	<para>
	  Overall, upstream traffic was optimized by a 24% and the
	  end-user experience was improved by 32%, thanks to higher
	  download rates in average. The solution was implemented
	  using the Squid Proxy on a server with a fine tuned
	  FreeBSD.
	</para>
      </sect4>

      <sect4>
	<title>Virtualization</title>
	<subtitle>National Housing and Habitat Bank</subtitle>
	<para>
	  BANAVIH (for its initials in spanish) is the official
	  institution in Venezuela for housing loans and
	  subsidy. They needed to optimize the hardware utilization in
	  their datacenter.
	</para>
	<para>
	  A total of 4 servers were freed and repurposed, thanks to
	  the application of the virtualization technology in
	  development and testing servers; saving thousands of dollars
	  in hardware adquirance. Red Hat Enterprise Linux and Xen
	  were the technologies used in this project.
	</para>
      </sect4>
      
      <sect4>
	<title>Migration of Email and Domain Controller services to
	Open Source Solutions</title>
	<subtitle>CONVIASA</subtitle>
	<para>
	  CONVIASA is a venezuelan airline. The objectives of the
	  project were the migration of email services and primary
	  domain controller to open source solutions.
	</para>
	<para>
	  The email services was migrated from third-party provider to
	  a self-hosted solution based on Red Hat Enterprise 5,
	  Postfix, Dovecot and Roundcube as web interface. The PDC was
	  implemented on Debian with Samba3 with group-based custom
	  profiles on workstations. Both services were integrated with
	  OpenLDAP as the backend for users identification and
	  authentication. The airline achieved the compliment 
	</para>
      </sect4>

      <sect4>
	<title>Web form for issuing policies</title>
	<subtitle>Pyugmao Fondos Administrados, C.A.</subtitle>
	<para>
	  Pyugmao is a risk manager company, providing Civil Liability
	  Policies to their customers. They needed a centralized
	  system to generate policies.
	</para>
	<para>
	  A web form was developed in the Perl programming language
	  with the CGI interface and PostgreSQL for the database. The
	  company was able to increase their salesforce and to emit
	  more than ten times more policies monthly, compared to the
	  months before the implementation of the solution.
	</para>
      </sect4>
      
      <sect4>
	<title>Interface for BT-3000 Plus Chemistry Analyzer</title>
	<subtitle>Neat Systems, C.A.</subtitle>
	<para>
	  Neat Systems is a development company specialized in ERP
	  Software for hospitals and laboratories, running on the
	  Windows platform. The <emphasis>BT-3000 Plus Chemistry
	  Analyzer</emphasis> has a serial communication protocol via
	  DB9 COMM Port, which makes it difficult to integrate into
	  the TCP/IP network.
	</para>
	<para>
	  A webservice was developed, implementing the serial protocol
	  and making it available via HTTP. The solution was written
	  in Perl on Debian Linux, and embedded in a VirtualBox image,
	  so it can be run inside a Windows server.
	</para>
      </sect4>

	<sect4>
	  <title>Digicheck2</title>
	  <subtitle>Bayco, C.A.</subtitle>
	  <para>
	    Bayco is a security solutions provider for the banking
	    industry in Venezuela. They lost the control over a
	    product they owned, due to some discordance with the
	    former developers of the product. I was able to
	    reverse-engineering the product and implement it using
	    open source technologies. I gave them back the control
	    over the product by writing detailed documentation about
	    how their product works, how was developed and how can be
	    modified.
	  </para>
	  <para>
	    The rewrite was made with Perl, using the framework
	    Mojolicious, PortgreSQL and Debian Linux. A customization
	    of the debian-installer was made in order to include the
	    corporate image of Bayco. The functionality of the
	    product was to take a screenshot of face, check and id
	    document when a client goes to the bank to cash a check.
	  </para>
	</sect4>

	<sect4>
	  <title>High Availability in VoIP</title>
	  <subtitle>FIDES, C.A.</subtitle>
	  <para>
	    FIDES is a company providing medical services through a
	    call center. The requirement was a setup such that if the
	    main VoIP PBX server fails, the spare can't take more than
	    20 seconds for the failover.
	  </para>
	  <para>
	    The goal was achieved combining specialized hardware from
	    <trademark>Digium</trademark> and replication techniques
	    on Elastix.
	  </para>
	</sect4>

	<sect4>
	  <title>Load Balancing Cluster</title>
	  <subtitle>inmobilia.com</subtitle>
	  <para><emphasis>inmobilia.com</emphasis> is a real state web
	  portal with presence in 13 countries. The initial setup for
	  their portal went out of capacity when they reached 4 hits
	  per second. I designed for them a mixed cluster with virtual
	  and bare metal servers, with defined roles as
	  <foreignphrase>loadbalancers</foreignphrase>,
	  <foreignphrase>backends</foreignphrase> and
	  <foreignphrase>databases</foreignphrase>. I also leaded the
	  development team into the <emphasis>Git Branching
	  Model</emphasis> workflow, documented in <ulink
	  url="http://http://nvie.com/posts/a-successful-git-branching-model/">this
	  article by Vincent Driessen</ulink>. Finally, I configured
	  an Amazon S3 bucket for the bank of images of the portal
	  (about 160 GB by that time) and helped to integrate the
	  storage service in the portal.
	  </para>
	  <para>
	    The performance increased drastically, holding loads of
	    above 30 requests per second with no significant impact on
	    the servers, whose could handle up to 5 times such load
	    without penalties. This implementation is saving money by
	    using virtual servers for most of the hosts and not
	    requiring huge amounts of additional storage for backups.
	  </para>
	</sect4>

	<sect4>
	  <title>Recovery of files from <trademark>Glacier</trademark></title>
	  <subtitle>inmobilia.com</subtitle>
	  <para>
	    The development team of inmobilia.com tried to implement
	    the versioning feature from S3 service. However, they made
	    a mistake and sent all their images to Glacier, where they
	    are not available online. Even with paid support from AWS,
	    they were unable to recover the files.
	  </para>
	  <para>
	    Using the API from AWS S3 I wrote I script in Perl making
	    parallel request, which helped to recover the files 16
	    times faster than the time required if we used the methods
	    suggested by AWS support. You can take a look at the
	    script at https://github.com/granalberto/s3mu.
	  </para>
	</sect4>
	    
	  
	
    </sect3>
    </sect2>
  </sect1>  
  
  <sect1 label="">
    <title>Training: Specialized Courses and Certifications</title>
    <sect2 label="">
      <title>IT Courses and Certifications</title>
      <sect3 label="">
	<title>
	  Network Management
	</title>
	<segmentedlist>
	  <segtitle>Description</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Institution</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Instructor</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Duration</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Certification granted</segtitle>
	  <seglistitem>
	    <seg>
	      Best practices in technical and management aspect for
	      data and voice networks. Available tools, configuration
	      and use.
	    </seg>
	    <seg>
	      Central University of Venezuela - Faculty of Engineering
	    </seg>
	    <seg>
	      Prof. Vicenzo Mendillo (UCV)
	    </seg>
	    <seg>
	      32 hours
	    </seg>
	    <seg>
	      Certificate of approval
	    </seg>
	  </seglistitem>
	</segmentedlist>	  
      </sect3>
      <sect3 label="">
	<title>Linux Professional Certified Program</title>
	<segmentedlist>
	  <segtitle>Description</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Institution</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Instructor</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Duration</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Certificate granted</segtitle>
	  <seglistitem>
	    <seg>
	      Basic and advanced administration of Linux-based
	      operative systems. Theoretic and ideological roots of free
	      software movement. Unix-like environments tool set.
	    </seg>
	    <seg>
	      Higher Institute of Technological Studies and
	      Investigations (ISEIT)
	    </seg>
	    <seg>
	      Ing. Carlos García - Ing. Jesús Rivero
	    </seg>
	    <seg>
	      80 hours
	    </seg>
	    <seg>
	      Certified Linux Administrator Professional
	    </seg>
	  </seglistitem>
	</segmentedlist>
      </sect3>

      <sect3 label="">
	<title>Linux Security Professional</title>
	<segmentedlist>
	  <segtitle>Description</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Institution</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Instructor</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Duration</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Certificate granted</segtitle>
	  <seglistitem>
	    <seg>
	      Basis of information security concepts. Tools and
	      methodologies for security policies implementations.
	    </seg>
	    <seg>
	       Higher Institute of Technological Studies and
	      Investigations (ISEIT)
	    </seg>
	    <seg>
	      Ing. Ricardo Strusberg
	    </seg>
	    <seg>
	      32 hours
	    </seg>
	    <seg>
	      Certified Linux Security Administrator Professional 
	    </seg>
	  </seglistitem>
	</segmentedlist>
      </sect3>

      <sect3 label="">
	<title>Linux Networks Administrator</title>
	<segmentedlist>
	  <segtitle>Description</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Institution</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Instructor</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Duration</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Certificado Emitido</segtitle>
	  <seglistitem>
	    <seg>
	      Networking concepts, services and open source
	      implementations.
	    </seg>
	    <seg>
	      Higher Institute of Technological Studies and
	      Investigations (ISEIT)
	    </seg>
	    <seg>
	      Ing. Ernesto Hernandez-Novich
	    </seg>
	    <seg>
	      32 hours
	    </seg>
	    <seg>
	      Certified Linux Networks Administrator Professional
	    </seg>
	  </seglistitem>
	</segmentedlist>
      </sect3>

      <sect3 label="">
	<title>LPI Certification</title>
	<segmentedlist>
	  <segtitle>Institute</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Certificate granted</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>LPI ID</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Verification Code</segtitle>
	  <seglistitem>
	    <seg>Linux Professional Institute</seg>
	    <seg>Junior Linux Certified Professional (LPIC-1)</seg>
	    <seg>LPI000092165</seg>
	    <seg>k3z5ham8ph</seg>
	  </seglistitem>
	</segmentedlist>
      </sect3>
      
      <sect3 label="">
	<title>Agile Development Workshop with Python</title>
	<segmentedlist>
	  <segtitle>Description</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Institution</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Instructor</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Duration</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Certificate granted</segtitle>
	  <seglistitem>
	    <seg>
	      Tools for agile development of user interfaces with
	      Python
	    </seg>
	    <seg>
	      V Foro Mundial del Conocimiento Libre
	    </seg>
	    <seg>
	      Ing. Francisco Palm
	    </seg>
	    <seg>
	      8 hours
	    </seg>
	    <seg>
	      Certificate of participation
	    </seg>
	  </seglistitem>
	</segmentedlist>
      </sect3>
      
    </sect2>
    <sect2 label="">
      <title>Professional and Personal Growth Courses</title>

      <sect3 label="">
	<title>Voice and Diction</title>
	<segmentedlist>
	  <segtitle>Description</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Instructor</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Duration</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Certificate granted</segtitle>
	  <seglistitem>
	    <seg>
	      Voice manipulation for professional purposes.
	    </seg>
	    <seg>
	      Lic. Adriana Romero
	    </seg>
	    <seg>
	      8 hours
	    </seg>
	    <seg>
	      Certificate of Approval
	    </seg>
	  </seglistitem>
	</segmentedlist>
      </sect3>

      <sect3 label="">
	<title>Job Analysis</title>
	<segmentedlist>
	  <segtitle>Description</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Institution</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Duration</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Certificate granted</segtitle>
	  <seglistitem>
	    <seg>
	      Position Analysis
	    </seg>
	    <seg>
	      INCE
	    </seg>
	    <seg>
	      40 hours
	    </seg>
	    <seg>
	     Certificate of Approval
	    </seg>
	  </seglistitem>
	</segmentedlist>
      </sect3>

      <sect3 label="">
	<title>Psychology Applied to the Supervision</title>
	<segmentedlist>
	  <segtitle>Description</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Institution</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Duration</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Certificate granted</segtitle>
	  <seglistitem>
	    <seg>
	      Management of work situations and leadership.
	    </seg>
	    <seg>
	      INCE
	    </seg>
	    <seg>
	      20 hours
	    </seg>
	    <seg>
	     Certificate of Approval
	    </seg>
	  </seglistitem>
	</segmentedlist>
      </sect3>
      
      <sect3 label="">
	<title>Quality-oriented Management</title>
	<segmentedlist>
	  <segtitle>Description</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Institution</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Duration</segtitle>
	  <segtitle>Certificate granted</segtitle>
	  <seglistitem>
	    <seg>
	      Concepts and strategies for process
	      optimization. Continuous improvement.
	    </seg>
	    <seg>
	      INCE
	    </seg>
	    <seg>
	      100 hours
	    </seg>
	    <seg>
	     Certificate of Approval
	    </seg>
	  </seglistitem>
	</segmentedlist>
      </sect3>
    </sect2>
  </sect1>

  <colophon>
    <title>About this document</title>
    <para>
      This document was produced using the <link
      xlink:href="https://docbook.org">DocBook 5</link> schema with
      <link
      xlink:href="https://github.com/docbook/xslt10-stylesheets">XSL
      stylesheets</link>, <link
      xlink:href="https://www.gnu.org/s/emacs">Emacs</link> as text
      editor, <link
      xlink:href="https://xmlsoft.org/xslt/xsltproc.html">xsltproc</link>
      for generating HTML 5 and <link
      xlink:href="https://xmlgraphics.apache.org/fop/">Apache
      FOP</link> for its <link
      xlink:href="https://granalberto.github.io/pdf/ajmp-cv-en.pdf">publication
      in PDF</link>. I'm also including a CSS Stylesheet from <link
      xlink:href="https://neat.joeldare.com/">Neat CSS</link> for a
      better look and feel on the web. Thank you all for your great
      work, guys!
    </para>
    <para>
      You can check the source code for this document in <link
      xlink:href="https://github.com/granalberto/cv/blob/master/docbook5/ajmp-cv-en.xml">Github</link>
    </para>
  </colophon>
</article>
